<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jonatha Daguerre Vasconcelos</title>
    <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jonatha Daguerre Vasconcelos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 20:53:21 -0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IO&#39;s - A Saga de um Processador</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/a-saga-de-um-processador/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 20:53:21 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/a-saga-de-um-processador/</guid>
      <description>O &amp;ldquo;IO&amp;rsquo;s - A Saga de um Processador&amp;rdquo;, foi uma websérie animada criado pelo Guto Garcia, e produzida pela Primo Comunicação entre 2002 e 2005, com o total de 5 episódios.
A websérie foi um sucesso estrondoso na internet não só no Brasil, mas também em outros países, chegando ao ponto se ser exibido nos festivais como Brasil Flash Festival 2.000 (finalista, entre os 10 melhores), Animamundiweb 2003 (1º lugar) e Sundance Online Film Festival, além nos sites dos bloggers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isaac Asimov - A Última Pergunta</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/asimov-the-last-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 08:25:59 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/asimov-the-last-question/</guid>
      <description>The Last Question (pt-br: A Última Pergunta) é um conto de ficção científica de Isaac Asimov. Sua primeira publicação foi na edição de novembro de 1956 da revista Science Fiction Quarterly e, a partir de então, teve diversas aparições em compilações, como Nove Amanhãs (1959), O Melhor de Isaac Asimov (1973) e Sonhos de Robô, assim como na retrospectiva Opus 100 (1969). É uma parte desconexa de uma série de contos sobre o computador ficcional chamado Multivac.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 22:22:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/books/</guid>
      <description>2025 Reading Challenge     Jonatha has read 2 books toward his goal of 12 books.  hide  2 of 12 (16%)  view books     .gr_grid_container { /* customize grid container div here. eg: width: 500px; */ } .gr_grid_book_container { /* customize book cover container div here */ float: left; width: 98px; height: 160px; padding: 0px 0px; overflow: hidden; }   The books I&#39;ve been reading  Jonatha&#39;s favorite books » Share book reviews and ratings with Jonatha, and even join a book club on Goodreads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How HTTPS Works</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/how-https-works-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 21:19:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/how-https-works-en/</guid>
      <description>Another great comics project from DNSimple:
 Have you ever wondered why a green lock icon appears on your browser URL bar? And why is it important? We did too, and this comic is for you!
Follow the adventures of Certificat, Browserbird, and Compugter as they explain why HTTPS is crucial for the future of the web and how it all works together.
Don&amp;rsquo;t let the bad crabs get you (you&amp;rsquo;ll know what we mean in the comic).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How DNS Works</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/how-dns-works-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 21:20:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/how-dns-works-en/</guid>
      <description>A fun and colorful explanation of how DNS works, by DNSimple.
 Oficial web site: https://howdns.works</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 23:53:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/about/</guid>
      <description>Português | English
With passion for solving problems and constantly seeking excellence, Jonatha has led several initiatives throughout his career.
With 10+ years of experience in software engineering, working with different stacks on national and international projects, Jonatha combines experience in several technologies and coding practices with a strong knowledge in infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sobre</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/sobre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 23:53:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/sobre/</guid>
      <description>Português | English
Apaixonado por solucionar problemas e em busca constante pela excelência, Jonatha liderou diversas iniciativas ao longo de sua carreira.
Com mais de 10 anos de experiência em engenharia de software, trabalhando com diferentes stacks em projetos nacionais e internacionais, Jonatha alia experiência em diversas tecnologias e práticas de programação com forte conhecimento em infraestrutura.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 20:12:21 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/projects/</guid>
      <description> Português | English
Some projects Here you can find some of my projects. For more code related projects please take a look at my github.
Web Pages  My Name Fuel Cost Splitter The Last Question Countdown React Sokoban  Developer tools  Docker System Admin and Troubleshooting Toolkit Django Logger Panel Simple Mock Server Driloader Unittest Prettify Python Cookiecutter  CLI  Brokerage Statement Parser Brazil NFe Scanner Metroclima database CLI tool PyPoABus  Documents  Portuguese translation of How To Become A Hacker Portuguese translation of The Glider: A Universal Hacker Emblem Pescar Project - GNU/Linux (class material)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projetos</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/projetos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 20:12:21 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/projetos/</guid>
      <description> Português | English
Alguns Projetos Aqui você encontra alguns dos meus projetos. Para mais projetos relacionados à código, dê uma olhada no meu github.
Páginas Web  My Name Fuel Cost Splitter The Last Question Countdown React Sokoban  Ferramentas para Desenvolvedores  Docker System Admin and Troubleshooting Toolkit Django Logger Panel Simple Mock Server Driloader Unittest Prettify Python Cookiecutter  CLI  Brokerage Statement Parser Brazil NFe Scanner Metroclima database CLI tool PyPoABus  Documentos  Como se Tornar um Hacker (Tradução) Glider: Um Emblema Hacker Universal (Tradução) GNU/Linux - Projeto Pescar (Material de apoio)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubunchu: A Manga about Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/ubunchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 20:12:21 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/ubunchu/</guid>
      <description>For those who like to learn having fun, there is a great tip:
 &amp;ldquo;Ubunchu!&amp;rdquo; is a Japanese manga series by Hiroshi Seo featuring Ubuntu Linux. Three school students in a system-admin club are getting into Ubuntu!
 Offical site: https://seotch.wordpress.com/ubunchu/
Translations available at: http://divajutta.com/doctormo/ubunchu/c1.html
Currently there are 8 episodes released and 7 with english translation.
Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Warriors of the Net</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/warriors-of-the-net-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 20:12:21 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/warriors-of-the-net-en/</guid>
      <description>Did you ever wonder how the Internet works? How does a router look like? What color does a IP packet have and how does it travel through a firewall? All the answers and many more can be found in the Warriors of the net movie. The movie is available in many different languages and it is the perfect tool for introducing Internet to novice users.
 Oficial web site: http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
