<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jonatha Daguerre Vasconcelos</title>
    <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jonatha Daguerre Vasconcelos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 21:19:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How HTTPS Works</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/how-https-works-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 21:19:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/how-https-works-en/</guid>
      <description>Another great comics project from DNSimple:
 Have you ever wondered why a green lock icon appears on your browser URL bar? And why is it important? We did too, and this comic is for you!
  Follow the adventures of Certificat, Browserbird, and Compugter as they explain why HTTPS is crucial for the future of the web and how it all works together.
  Don&amp;rsquo;t let the bad crabs get you (you&amp;rsquo;ll know what we mean in the comic).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How DNS Works</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/how-dns-works-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 21:20:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/how-dns-works-en/</guid>
      <description>A fun and colorful explanation of how DNS works, by DNSimple.
 Oficial web site: https://howdns.works</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 23:53:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/about/</guid>
      <description>Português | English
Working as software developer for 7+ years, Jonatha accumulated experience in many different languages, frameworks, tools and processes. His passion for problem solving and automation led him to be a reference in automation, infrastucture, GNU/Linux and RegEx among his co-workers.
He holds a Bachelor’s degree in Information Systems and a MBA in Data Science/Big Data from PUCRS.
Currently, he works at ADP as Software Architect, building solutions to support the company&amp;rsquo;s global infrastructure team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sobre</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/sobre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 23:53:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/sobre/</guid>
      <description>Português | English
Trabalhando como desenvolvedor de software por mais de 7 anos, Jonatha acumulou experiência em diversos linguagens, frameworks, ferramentas e processos. Sua paixão pela solução de problemas e automação o levou a ser uma referência em automação, infraestrutura, GNU / Linux e RegEx entre seus colegas de trabalho.
É formado em Sistemas de Informação e possui MBA em Ciência de Dados / Big Data pela PUCRS.
Atualmente, ele trabalha na ADP como Arquiteto de Software, criando soluções para dar suporte à equipe de infraestrutura global da empresa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 16:02:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/principles/</guid>
      <description>Português | English
My Principles for Life and Work Inspired by the book &amp;ldquo;Principles&amp;rdquo; by Ray Dalio, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reflecting on the principles of life and work that have led my personal and professional life so far. Several months after finishing the book, it was possible to me to write my own principles.
It is a constantly evolving list, showing the behaviors and beliefs that worked for me. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe it is a list to be copied by other people, but I think it may serve as inpiration for those who have not yet reflected on their own principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Princípios</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/principios/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 16:02:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/principios/</guid>
      <description>Português | English
Meus Princípios de Vida e Trabalho Inspirado pelo livro Princípios, de Ray Dalio, venho refletindo constantemente sobre os princípios de vida e de trabalho que têm conduzido minha vida pessoal e profissional até o momento. Após vários meses da finalização do livro, consegui colocar no papel os meus próprios princípios.
Trata-se de uma lista em constante evolução, que reflete os comportamentos e crenças que deram certo para mim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 20:12:21 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/projects/</guid>
      <description>Português | English
Some projects Here you can find some of my projects. For more code related projects please take a look at my github.
Web Pages  My Name Fuel Cost Splitter The Last Question Countdown React Sokoban  Developer tools  Docker System Admin and Troubleshooting Toolkit Django Logger Panel Simple Mock Server Driloader Unittest Prettify  CLI  Metroclima database CLI tool PyPoABus  Documents  Portuguese translation of How To Become A Hacker Portuguese translation of The Glider: A Universal Hacker Emblem Pescar Project - GNU/Linux (class material)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projetos</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/projetos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 20:12:21 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/projetos/</guid>
      <description>Português | English
Alguns Projetos Aqui você encontra alguns dos meus projetos. Para mais projetos relacionados à código, dê uma olhada no meu github.
Páginas Web  My Name Fuel Cost Splitter The Last Question Countdown React Sokoban  Ferramentas para Desenvolvedores  Docker System Admin and Troubleshooting Toolkit Django Logger Panel Simple Mock Server Driloader Unittest Prettify  CLI  Metroclima database CLI tool PyPoABus  Documentos  Como se Tornar um Hacker (Tradução) Glider: Um Emblema Hacker Universal (Tradução) GNU/Linux - Projeto Pescar (Material de apoio)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubunchu: A Manga about Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/ubunchu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 20:12:21 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/ubunchu/</guid>
      <description>For those who like to learn having fun, there is a great tip:
 &amp;ldquo;Ubunchu!&amp;rdquo; is a Japanese manga series by Hiroshi Seo featuring Ubuntu Linux. Three school students in a system-admin club are getting into Ubuntu!
 Offical site: https://seotch.wordpress.com/ubunchu/
Translations available at: http://divajutta.com/doctormo/ubunchu/c1.html
Currently there are 8 episodes released and 7 with english translation.
Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Warriors of the Net</title>
      <link>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/warriors-of-the-net-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 20:12:21 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jonatha.daguerre.com.br/blog/warriors-of-the-net-en/</guid>
      <description>Did you ever wonder how the Internet works? How does a router look like? What color does a IP packet have and how does it travel through a firewall? All the answers and many more can be found in the Warriors of the net movie. The movie is available in many different languages and it is the perfect tool for introducing Internet to novice users.
 Oficial web site: http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
